Guide to the Stanford University, Financial Aid Office, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Financial Aid Office, records
1904-1979
SC0120
Stanford University. Financial Aid Office.
3 Linear feet
Includes correspondence, annual reports, and committee minutes, 1935-1970.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Financial Aids Office, 1974.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Financial Aids Office has charge of matters relating to the obtaining, managing, and dispensing of scholarship, fellowship, loan and other assistance to undergraduates and some graduates at Stanford.
Description of the Collection
Includes correspondence, annual reports, and committee minutes, 1935-1970.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Financial Aid Office.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-1996-101
  The records are closed for 75 years following their date of creation. As of 1996, only those records dated 1921 and earlier are open to researchers.
  - Letterpress book: outgoing correspondence and memos of the Committee on Scholarship; most letters signed by Charles H. Gilbert, 1904-1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Special Department Reports on individual students, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - List of students and action taken, December 1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1928-29 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Scholarship, January - July 1935 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1935/36 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1936/37 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1937/38 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1938/39 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1939/40 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1940/41 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1941/42 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1942/43 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1943/44 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1944/45 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1945/46 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1946/47 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1947/48 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1948/49 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1949/50 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1950/51 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1951/52 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Scholarship, 1952/53 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Note on split of committee, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Financial Awards, 1953/54 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Financial Awards, 1954/55 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Financial Awards, 1955/56 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Financial Awards, 1956/57 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Financial Awards, 1957/58 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Financial Awards, 1958/59 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Financial Awards, 1959/60 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dean’s binder: index and minutes, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dean’s binder: minutes, 1955/56 - 1956/57 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Dean’s binder: minutes, 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 13)